Chathura Rubasingha

Front-End Developer

Front End Developer with two years of experience working with JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, and HTML/CSS to deliver exceptional customer experiences. Adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction.

Educational Background

B.Sc. (Hons) in Information Technology • Jan 2020 - July 2024

University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

- GPA 3.6

Work Experience

Junior Front-End Developer - Part-Time

July 2023 - July 2024 | Remote Hasthiya IT

- · Successfully integrated a web-based Queue Management System for the Department for Registration of Persons, Sri Lanka, reducing customer wait times by 50%.
- · Led the design and implementation of Cleaner Connect, a platform that streamlined service management, resulting in a 25% increase in service efficiency and user satisfaction.
- Optimized the Seguros web app by implementing secure payment and policy enforcement mechanisms, increasing transaction reliability and user trust by 45%.

Trainee Front-End Developer

Jan 2023 - Jun 2023 | Remote Hasthiya IT

- · Actively participated in an agile environment, including daily stand-up meetings and regular client meetings, which led to a 40% increase in production efficiency.
- Designed front-end code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery to create a responsive web application that works across desktops, tablets, and 20+ other devices.
- Hand-coded embedded stylesheets into 20+ Javascript interfaces and reduced load times by 75% in the first month of implementation.
- Developed and launched PawprintID, a comprehensive web application for pet management, which streamlined data entry and tracking, improving user efficiency by 30%.

Completed Projects

- Fleet Management System React
- Queue Management React
- · Cleaner Connect React
- MCQUI React
- · Seguros React
- PawprintID React

Researches

- Image-Based Tea Quality Analysis - Python, OpenCV
- · Virtual Reality for Medical Training
- Component Architecture and Design Patterns

Contact

Katubedda, Moratuwa +94 77 812-6872 rubasinghe99cpk@gmail.com LinkedIn/chathura-rubasinghe Github/ChathuraRubasingha Portfolio/chathurarubasinghe

Technical Skills

Web Development:

• HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJS, NextJS, Redux, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, JQuery

Programming Languages:

· Java, Python, C

Version Control:

• Git

Design and Prototyping:

Figma

Project Management:

· Jira, Trello

API Testing:

· Postman, RESTful APIs

Development Tools:

· Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA

Soft Skills

- · Problem Solving
- Team Collaboration
- Communication
- Agile Methodologies

Languages

- Sinhala (Fluent)
- English (Proficient)

Referee

H.M.Rashminda Bandara CEO - HASTHIYA Company +94 71 256 0246 irashminda@hotmail.com